Ryan Monteith

Senior Picture Editor / Story Editor

ryan@bandofcutters.com 647.273.3154

ORGANIZATIONS

Canadian Cinema Editors

Metis Nation of Ontario

SUMMARY

Seasoned freelance picture editor with 20+ years in unscripted TV and documentaries. With a love for telling stories through the craft of editing since childhood, Ryan's work reflects a deep commitment to authentic storytelling and collaborative success in fast paced environments.

EXPERIENCE

United Gangs of America S2 (Vice), Vice Media *Picture Editor, True Crime Series*

Dec 2024 - Current

2 x Episodes: Edited on Premiere Pro

50K First Dates (Prime Video), Peacock Alley *Picture Editor*, *Docu–Series*

July 2024 - Nov 2024

2 x Episodes: Edited on Premiere Pro, Director: Brent Hodge

The Passionate Eye (CBC), Peacock Alley *Picture Editor, Story Editor, Writer, Documentary*

March 2024 - July 2024

1 x Episode: Harder Better Faster Stronger, Edited on Premiere Pro,

Director: Brent Hodge

Mr. Dressup: Doc (Prime Video), marblemedia *Picture Editor*, *Feature Documentary*

Nov 2022 - Jan 2023

Mr. Dressup: The Magic of Make Believe premiered at TIFF 2023 winning the People's Choice Documentary Award

Luxe Listings Toronto (Prime Video), MEM *Picture Editor, Documentary – Reality TV*

Oct 2023 - Dec 2024

2 x Episodes

SKILLS

Avid Media Composer

Adobe Premiere Pro

Factual / Unscripted

Storytelling / Writing

Documentary / Docu-Series / Reality / Reality Competition

AWARDS

3 X Winner, Canadian Cinema Editor Award for The Amazing Race Canada, Top Chef Canada & Best in Miniature S2

1 X Childrens Emmy Nominee for a 2024 "Outstanding Editing for a Multi-Cam Live Action Program"

12 X Canadian Screen Award Nominee for Best Picture Editing in a Reality / Competition Program or Series

3 X Canadian Cinema Editors Award Nominee for Best
Picture Editing in a Reality /
Competition Program or Series

All Round Champion (BYUtv / TVO), marblemedia

Picture Editor, Competition Reality

Nov 2020 - March 2024

5 x Episodes across seasons 2-6

Nomination for 2024 Childrens Emmy in the "outstanding editing for a multi-cam live action program" category

Best in Miniature S1 & S2 (CBC), marblemedia Supervising Editor / Story Editor, Competition Reality

July 2021 - Jan 2023

Story Editor 2 x Episodes S2 / Supervising Editor 8 x Episodes S2 Lead Editor 2 x Episodes S1

The Amazing Race Canada (CTV), Insight Productions Senior Editor /Lead Editor, Competition Reality

May 2014 - Aug 2023

Lead Editor: 12 x Episodes, 7 x Seasons

Senior/Supervising Editor: 11 x Episodes, Season 9

Drink Masters (Netflix), marblemedia

Picture Editor, Competition Reality

Jan 2022 - Feb 2022 1 x Episode 3

Big Brother Canada (Global), Insight Productions Supervising Editor, Competition Reality

Feb 2013 - May 2023

Supervising Editor: 100+ x Episodes, 10 x Seasons

Picture Editor: 20 x Episodes, Season 11

Dragons Den S15 & S16 (CBC), CBC

Picture Editor, Reality

Aug 2020 - Oct 2021

The Bachelor Canada S3 (W), Good Human Productions *Lead Editor*, *Reality*

May 2017 - Oct 2017

3 x Episodes

Top Chef Canada S6 (Food Network), Insight Productions *Picture Editor, Competition Reality*

Nov 2017 - Feb 2018

2 x Episodes

MasterChef Canada S1 & S2 (CTV), Proper Television *Lead Editor*, *Competition Reality*

Aug 2013 - Feb 2016 3 x Episodes

Farmhouse Facelift S3 (HGTV), Be Collective Media *Lead Editor*, *Reno-Reality*

Mar 2023 - Apr 2023 2 x Episodes

The Deed S1 & The Deed Chicago S1 (CNBC), Cineflix *Picture Editor*, *Reality*

Aug 2016 - Jan 2017 3 x Episodes

American Beauty Star S2 (Lifetime, A&E), Insight **Post Producer,** Competition Reality

Aug 2018 - Feb 2019

Edited & Managed Post Production team through 10 x Episodes

Race Against the Tide S1 (CBC), marblemedia *Picture Editor, Competition Reality*

Jan 2021 - Mar 2021

Hockey Wives S1 (W Network), Bristow Global Media *Picture Editor*, *Docu-Soap*

Aug 2014 - Oct 2014

2 x Episodes

Brave New Girls (E! Channel), Peacock Alley Ent.

Picture Editor, Docu-Soap

May 2013 - Oct 2013

Hello Goodbye (CBC), FORTÉ Entertainment *Picture Editor*, *Reality*

Oct 2015 - Dec 2015 2 x Episodes

At the Table with..., Fir Valley Productions *Picture Editor, Documentary Series*

2007 - 2009

13 x Episodes

Complete linear work history available: linkedin.com/in/ryanmonteitheditor

EDUCATION

Sheridan College, School of Arts, Animation & Design Media Arts Diploma

1997 - 2000